<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">search</string>


    <string name="txt">What is left of Pop after sixty years? What is left of a story which began in 1947 with the Big Bang of Paolozzi’s gun and was continued by Alloway’s ‘independence’ before passing through the ‘aesthetic nazism’ of which Crispolti accused Warhol: A story which ended up with Livingstone’s potentially infinite ‘continuing history’?
The real question to ask is – what is left out of Pop? The answer is: nothing. Pop in fact has lost its capital letter and camouflages itself; it corresponds with a collective horizon, it pretends to fade away but instead has just blended itself into the background, imposing itself on all phenomena. Pop pretends to become a hologram when instead it is reality, which is becoming more like a hologram thanks to pop culture.
Everything is pop. Even art, of every kind, becomes ‘items’: telegraphic impulses that are transmittable and exchangeable. Real Pop, on the other hand, meaning art that is actually intended to be pop, assumes various forms which can be divided into four subcategories:

1. Classical Pop, this draws inspiration from the 50’s, 60’s and 80’s (1980’s Pop and what followed thereafter marked a period of decline, a sort of voluntaristic neoclassicism).
2. pop, with a small p, refers to the phenomenon of today’s undifferentiated popular culture.
3. pop or Pop artists (subcategory of points 1 and 2) who knowingly analyse collective thought. They can be divide into celebrative, critical and, as in the case of American Pop, ambiguous.
4. Organic pop artists (another subcategory of points 1 and 2).  Lackey’s of the system, integrated and accepted who confront the visual-cultural scene without putting it into doubt. A significant portion of young Italian artists belong to this category.

Stuart Semple belongs to the third category. He mixes ambiguity and critical spirit, pushing the accelerator of excess in a shocking way. He makes détournements but doesn’t disfigure. He remains autonomous in recording pop culture, without ever acritically adhering to pop; he re-elaborates it in his own personal universe. His reference point is that of a voluntaristic and complete artist. His items are music, fashion, literature, cinema and youth subculture. The point in his favour, compared with many others, is the sincerity (but not naivety) of his work, the willingness of sublimation.
His ambiguity allows spectators to decide whether what they are seeing is celebrative or critical of mass culture. What is certain is that you can easily get lost in Semple’s many worlds: entering into those which the title of one of his series’ defined ‘post-Pop Paradise’ and which I would define as ‘artificial paradises’; paradises which today are impossible to escape from, paradises which don’t blunt but moreover hyperbolize impulses, with the aim of creating awareness of visual contemporary reality.
Semple, who is English and was born in 1980, is nonetheless a child of the grandiosely decadent American Pop season of the 80’s, which reinterpreted those of the previous decades. Of this ascendance he maintains non-conformism which allowed the mixing of Pop, Bad Painting, graffitism and post-urban culture.</string>
</resources>